Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number one.
We are going to deal with the big sell, so we need to find the upper bound for the function f of the
first function that we have is.
Three of n equal to three and plus eight.
Gay.
This is the first function we need to find the upper bound of this function.
OK.
If we look on this function, what is the highest order of this function?
We have two terms the three and.
And the eight, OK?
Three am and here at eight times and two powers here and here and the power one, so and to power one
is greater than and power to zero.
So we took and to power one as the biggest SIM and the three plus three and one.
This means we remove that constant and three and plus eight is less than four.
And because three and plus eight is less than four, and if we neglect eight three and is less than
or equal to four, and that's a true and and now we remove the constants.
And is that notation of and for the three and plus eight?
OK, we see is equal to four.
See, equal to four and and zero, equal to eight.
OK.
This is very important to understand.
This is the first example.
Don't worry, we will clarify in the next exercise.
If we have the second function, F, of an equal to any square plus one, what is the highest order
of this function?
We have two terms and squared and one which is multiplied by n0.
So we took and squared and square plus one is less than two to power and square because we neglect this
and we add one to the.
The same order.
OK, so and square +1 less than or equal to power and square to the power hour and power to look for
every and greater than one.
Therefore, the big old notation of this function is equal to and square.
It's very simple.
We are just getting the highest order of the function, the highest an order of the function.
And the C C is equal to here.
Two and that and zero is equal to one, this is the.
It's very simple.
OK, guys, we are going also to make an example three, so find the upper bound for the function and
two power four plus one hundred and.
One hundred and a square.
Plus.
Fifty.
OK.
So please, guys, think about it.
This function of and contains and power for plus one and squared plus 50.
How to solve this?
How to find the upward fund in the same way.
Look at this function we have for a three terms one, two and three.
What is the highest order of this function?
What is the highest end of this function that we have and to power for?
OK, so what is multiplied by and the power for it is one.
So this function f of an is less than or equal to.
We increase the multiple at the one that multiplied by and power four by one one plus one is equal to
two.
And the highest degree is and power.
Four.
OK, so this function is less than.
And two and power four.
OK.
And.
And Square here is the highest functioning so of and of this function is and to power for and the constants
that we have is that are see equal to do because we have multiplied or we have added one to them, the
one that multiplied by and four.
So this is equal to C or this will determine the sea and no zero is equal to anything.
No, we don't care about these constants and zeros because our old concentration about all of us.
OK, so I need from you to understand how to create a how to get of and for every function.
OK.
Oh, and here.
It is over and OK, this is the complex.
This is the big mutation.
Another examples consider the function f of an air equal to do and cube minus two and squared.
We have two and the cube minus two and the square because we have two terms here.
The highest term is and power cube since we have.
Tooth and cube minus two and a square, so and cube.
To two and Cube is being decreased, so this function do and the cube minus two and the square is less
than or equal to any cube.
We don't need to put here three and like here.
No, we don't need about to make this.
We need to put two and square two and cube.
OK.
Because to end, the cube is decreased by minus two and the square.
So remember four take an example and equal to one two minus two times one minus two times one is equal
to zero is equal less than or equal to do.
Yes, because zero less than two I substituted one inside this.
We don't care about this function.
We only get about the big own mutation of this function.
It is all of the three because it is the highest degree.
OK.
This is the big O notation of this function, where C is equal to do this, that constant and end zero
is equal to one.
OK, now another two examples that we are going to make in this exercise, find the upper bound of f
of an equal to N.
Here is the only term that we have in this function.
So and as less than or equal to N, so it is of big own rotation.
All of an OK was equal to one, the constant equal to one because he is and is multiplied by one here
and and zero equal to one.
It's various.
Let's choose another example f of an equal to 410
410 is less than or equal 410.
OK.
It's very simple.
410.
Now, this for all and greater than one, this means 410 is equal to all of one.
So this is the bit of one.
This is the notation of all of one.
OK.
We see equal to one and n0 equal to one.
So what we have done in this exercise is is understanding the big O notation calculation for this,
for these functions.
So how to calculate the fine that of and how to get the highest degree of of.
And in this exercise.
So we have solved these of annotations, and it's very important to understand this and to learn about
the role of annotation.
And in the next videos, we are going to learn more about these notations and work with more exercises.
So don't worry, we are going to make this very simple in the next videos when we deal with the complexity.
So what if what I need from you to understand that the big O notation for any function is the highest
degree that it contains?
And.